

Native English Speaker from the United States who has been living in Madrid for almost 8 years and has a working permit for Spain. Professional, hardworking, responsible and personable who is also able to adapt easily and strives to reach her full potential.

Education:

- Masters of Bilingual and Multicultural Education, June 2017
 University of Alcalá, Alcalá de Henares, Spain
- Bachelors of Science, Biology and Spanish, May 2014
 Albright College, Reading, Pennsylvania, United States of America

Professional Experience:

- English Teacher and Coordinator, March 2022- June 2022
 Colegio Trilema Sagrada Familia
 Madrid, Spain
- English Teacher, September 2021- March 2022
 Ellaluna American School
 Madrid, Spain
- English Teacher, October 2020- April 2021
 Helen Doron Valdebebas
 Madrid, Spain
- Language and Culture Assistant, September 2020- April 2021
 Beda Program
 Colegio Maristas Chamberí
 Madrid, Spain
- Language and Culture Assistant, September 2019- June 2020
 Beda Program
 Colegio Santa Maria del Carmen and Colegio Stella Maris
 Madrid, Spain
- English Teacher, Summer 2018
 The London School
 Summer Camp
 Piadena and Calcio, Italy

• English Teacher, Summer 2017

The London School Summer Camp Mestre and Castelnovo di Sotto, Italy

• Language and Culture Assistant, September 2016- June 2017

Internship during Master's degree Colegio Nuestra Señora de Las Nieves Madrid, Spain

• Language and Culture Assistant, October 2014- June 2016 and October 2017- June 2019

Ministry of Education, Culture and Sport CEIP Ciudad de Roma Madrid, Spain

Other Activities:

• Public Health Internship, Summer 2014

Shadowed the staff of Reading Housing Authority helping residents, attending meetings and teaching wellness classes two times a week to children in neighborhoods of Reading Housing Authority while teaching wellness classes once a week to adults in the main building of Reading Housing Authority.

• Peer Tutor, Fall 2011-Spring 2014

Attended tutor training sessions, discipline meetings, and midpoint and end of the semester evaluations. Selected to tutor Spanish on the basis of academic skill, leadership, character, professor recommendations and the ability to communicate well with others. Collaborated with the faculty of the Spanish department and Academic Learning Center of Albright College.

• Study Group Leader, Fall 2013-Spring 2014

Led a weekly evening study group for beginning and intermediate Spanish classes while collaborating with professors outside of class and the Academic Learning Center of Albright College.

• Medical Externship at Reading Hospital, January 2013

Shadowed in the obstetrics and gynecology unit of the Reading Hospital alongside physicians, nurses, residents, and medical students. Throughout the month of January, participated in clinical rounds and observed deliveries and procedures in the labor and delivery unit. Also attended morning meetings, discussions, and listened to case studies. Outside of the Reading Hospital, at Albright College participated in discussion groups with other students involved in the externship and performed written assignments.

• Internship with Dr. Fredericka Heller of Women's Lifecycles in Reading, PA, Spring 2012 Shadowed Dr. Heller and staff for patient evaluations, examinations, and consultations.

• Study Abroad in Spain, Summer 2012

Program: The Center for Cross-Cultural Study

Summer Session 1: Sevilla-Spanish for the Health Professional

Summer Session 2: Alicante- High Advanced Spanish II at the University of Alicante